Okay, in the last uh video group I
showed you that
um an input could be hijacked if you
directly injected user input into your
inner HTML. They could someone could
hijack it and do some cross-ite
scripting, inject their own script and
it will run. And that's problematic cuz
I mean we need to build to-do lists. No,
but really we need to take user input
and we need to put it on the screen. And
so um I'm going to show you one of the
ways that you could do that. So let's
come over and take a look at the code.
So right now we have an element and we
are and we want it to be a list element
so that we can keep adding items to
this. In the past I converted this to a
div and then just directly appended text
content to it. And that filtered out any
script tags, anything like that that
someone could have injected. Um but it'd
be really nice to append list items kind
of like I'm doing here. Um so instead of
using inner HTML, we're going to use
something else. So, we still do want to
get their input. Um, that is valuable.
And so, we're going to keep grabbing the
input. We're going out to the DOM and
grabbing the input. Rather than using
inner HTML,
we are going to create a list item. So,
let's create our list item. So, we'll
say document
create
um
elements.
And then we need to give it a tag name.
And in this case, we want a list item.
So now we have created a list item. Um,
and let's actually store it in a
variable for now. We'll say my list item
equals we've now created a list item.
Once we've created it, we could access
the list item and set its text content
equal to uh the inputs value.
So, what we're saying is go out to the
DOM, grab the input,
create an element,
put the text content there, and notice
because we're setting text content, they
can no longer inject a button. And then
let's set the value back to nothing and
set the focus. And you would think that
this would work. So, we can say go
shopping, add item. Where did it go?
Well, if you think back to the video a
while ago that talked about HTML trees
and how everything needed to fall within
HTML tags and then within the body tags
and how there was a whole hierarchy of
tags. We've created a tag, but we
haven't put it anywhere. And that will
be the topic of the next